Register of the Robert Daniel Murphy papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Photographs, I
  - 2 prints of Robert Murphy, Dwight Eisenhower and Allied officers, North Africa, circa 1944; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Dwight Eisenhower, North Africa, 1943; 2 prints of Dwight Eisenhower and others; 2 prints of Dwight Eisenhower; 7 unidentified prints; 1 print of P.L. Barill, 1943; 1 print of P.L. Barill and others, North Africa, 1943. (Envelope Q)
  - 9 prints of Robert Murphy and others, North Africa, 1943; 1 print of Theodore Roosevelt, Jr., Louis Koeltz, and Terry Allen, 1943; 1 print of Elliott Roosevelt and tohers; 1 print of Robert McClure and others; 1 print of Terry Allen and others, 1942; 1 print of Theodore Roosevelt, Jr. and others; 1 print of Dwight Eisenhower, Omar Bradley and others, 1943; 1 print of Adolphe Menjou 1943. (Envelope R)
  - 10 prints of Robert Murphy, circa 1943; 1 print of Robert Murphy and Alphonse Juin, 1943; 1 print of George Marshall and others, 1943; 1 print of Dwight Eisenhower, F.N. Mason MacFarlane; 1 print of Omar Bradley, Henri Giraud and others, 1943; 1 print of Mark Clark, and the Sultan of Morocco, 1943; 1 print of Charles Collingwood and others, 1942; 2 prints of Robert Murphy, Dwight Eisenhower and others on occasion of Murphy receiving Distinguished Service Medal, January 9, 1943; 2 prints of Robert Murphy and Alphonse Juin. (Envelope mS)
  - 25 prints of Robert Murphy., circa 1945 (Envelope T)
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy and others; 2 prints of Murphy, circa 1945; 13 prints of inmates in U.S. Berlin Detention Camp, Nov., 1945; 3 prints of Murphy and others, circa 1945; 1 print of Murphy Lucius Clay and others; 2 unidentified prints; 3 prints of Clay and others; 1 print of Murphy, Clay and others, circa 1945; 1 unidentified print; 1 print of Murphy, Dwight Eisenhower, Lucius Clay, Georgii Zhukov, circa 1945; 1 print of Bernard Montgomery, Georgii Zhukov, Dwight Eisenhower, Robert Murphy and others, Berlin, 1945; 1 print of Lucius Clay, Andrei Vishinsky, Robert Murphy, Dwight Eisenhower, Georgii Zhukovl; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Andrei Vishinsky and others, circa 1945; 4 prints of Georgii Zhukov, Lucius Clay, Bernard Montgomery and others. (Envelope U)
  - 1 print of Georgii Zhukov, Bernard Montgomery, Joseph McNarney and others; 3 prints of Georgii Zhukov, Bernard Montgomery, George Marshall, Robert Murphy and others, circa 1945; 7 prints of Robert Murphy and others; 1 print of Bernard Montgomery and Georgii Zhukov; 1 print of Dwight Eisenhower and Georgii Zhukov, 4 prints of Georgii Zhukov and others; 4 unidentified prints, 1945; 1 print of Georgii Zhukov, 1945. (Envelope V)
  - 16 prints of Allied Control Council Headquarters, August 22, 1945; Allied Control Council Meeting, August, 1945: 1 print of Georgii Zhukov and others; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Dwight Eisenhower, Bernard Montgomery and others; 5 prints of Robert Murphy and others; 1 print of Lucius Clay and others; 1 print of Bernard Montgomery and others; 1 print of Allied leaders at flag-raising ceremony; 2 unidentified prints. (Envelope W)
  - 1 print of Eleanor Roosevelt, Lucius Clay, Robert Murphy and others, 1946; 1 print of Joseph McNarney and others, 1946; 26 prints of RObert Murphy and others, St. Moritz, 1946; 3 prints of Robert Murphy, 1946; 5 prints of Maurice pope and others, circa 1946; 4 prints of a parade; 1 print of plaque commemorating Robert Murphy's work in North Africa; 2 prints of Louis Mountbatten and others, circa 1946; 1 print of table setting. (Envelope X)
  - 13 prints of Harry Truman's visit to Berlin (?) circa 1945 (on 4 of the prints Generals Dwight Eisenhower, Omar Bradley and George Patton are with President Truman); 1 print of Robert Murphy, Dwight Eisenhower and others; 1 print of Averell Harriman; 1 print of Averell Harriman, Albert Wedemeyer and others, circa 1946; 5 prints of Robert Murphy. Lucius Clay and others. 1946; 1 print of Robert Murphy in Moscow, 1946; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others, Berlin, 1946; 1 print of James F. Byrnes, Alfred Vandenberg, Tom Connally, Robert Murphy and others, circa 1946; 1 print of Lucius Clay, Tom Connally and others, circa 1946; 2 prints of Robert Murphy, Lucius Clay and others, Germany, 1946; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Ernest Bevin, Mark Clark, F.T. Gusev, Maurice Couve de Murville and others, London, circa 1946. (Envelope Y)
  - 6 prints of Lucius Clay and others, Berlin, 1946; 13 prints of Lucius Clay, Dwight Eisenhower, Robert Murphy and others, Berlin, 1946; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Lucius Clay and others, circa 1946; 3 prints of Robert Murphy and others, 1946. (Envelope Z)
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy; 2 prints of Robert Murphy and others; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Lucius Clay, Vassily Sokolovsky, Leipzig; 6 prints of Robert Murphy and Lucius Clay and others; 1 print of Lucius Clay and others; 11 prints of conference; 1 print of scene in Frankfurt, Germany, 1946 (Envelope AA)
  - 2 prints of a Director's Meeting, Office of the Military Government for Germany, United States (OMGUS)., May 4, 1946 (Envelope mBB)
  - 2 prints of Herbert Hoover, Hugh Gibson, Mark Clark, Clement Atlee, Robert Murphy and others, 1947; 3 prints of Herbert Hoover, Lucius Clay, Hugh Gibson, and Joseph McNarney; 2 prints of Robert Murphy and others, 1947; 1 print of Berchtesgaden, Germany, June, 1947; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Lucius Clay and others 1947; 4 prints of Robert Murphy and family, circa 1947; 5 prints of Robert Murphy and others at an Allied Control Council meeting, May 31, 1947; 2 prints of Robert Murphy, Lucius Clay and others at Allied Control Council Meeting, May 31, 1947. (Envelope CC)
  - 30 prints of Robert Murphy, Lucius Clay and others, circa 1947; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others, circa 1947; 1 print of Robert Murphy; 1 print of Lucius Clay, Robert Murphy and others, May 24, 1947; 2 prints of Robert Murphy and John W. Snyder, September 25, 1947; 2 prints of Lucius Clay and John W. Snyder. (Envelope DD)
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy and Lucius Clay, Germany, 1947; 1 print of Mark Clark, 1947; 1 print of Joseph McNarney; 3 prints of Andrei Vishinsky, Robert Murphy and others, Moscow (?), circa 1947; 1 print of George Marshall, V.M. Molotov and Andrei Vishinsky; 2 prints of Robert Murphy and others; 4 unidentified prints; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Lucius Clay and others, Allied Control Council meeting, May, 1947; 1 print of the Soviet Delegation, May 1947; 2 prints of Robert Murphy, 1947. (Envelope EE)
  - 2 prints of Robert Murphy, Lucius Clay and others, Germany., May, 1947 (Envelope FF)
  - 1 print of the American Research Hospital, Krakow, Poland; 1 drawing of the American Research Hospital, Krakow, circa 1947., undated (Envelope mGG)
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy and others, May, 1947; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others, 1948; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others, 1948; 1 print of George Marshall, John Foster Dulles, Lucius Clay and others, 1 print of Robert Murphy and Carmel Offie; 2 prints of Robert Murphy, Carmel Offie and others; 3 prints of George Marshall and others; 1 print of V.M. Molotov and others; 8 prints of conference, 1948; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Wong Shih-Chieh and others, October 15, 1948; 3 prints of John Foster Dulles, Lucius Clay, Robert Murphy and others; 1 print of Robert Murphy, John Foster Dulles, and Lucius Clay; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others, Dec., 1948. (Envelope HH)
  - 1 print of John F. Dulles, Brian Robertson, and Lucius Clay, October 15, 1948; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others, circa 1948; 1 miscellaneous print; 13 prints of Robert Murphy, circa 1948; 17 postcard prints of Robert Murphy and others, circa 1948; 1 print of John F. Dulles, Robert Murphy and others at the Bizonal Conference, Frankfurt, Germany, circa 1948. (Envelope II)
  - 9 postcard prints of the United States Constabulary School, Germany, 1948; 23 prints of Robert Murphy and others, circa 1948; 1 print of Robert Murphy, circa 1948; 13 prints of a wedding in Berlin, circa 1948., undated (Envelope JJ)
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy and others, circa 1949; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others, July 4, 1949; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others Council of Foreign Ministers, May, 1949; 3 prints of Robert Murphy and others, circa 1949; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others at the George Washington U. Alumni Assn. meeting, 1949; 3 prints of Robert Murphy and others, July, 1949; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others, circa 1949. (Envelope KK)
  - 1 print of Mr. and Mrs. Robert Murphy and others, Bavaria, 1949. 1 print of Murphy and others, Bavaria, 1949; 2 prints of Robert Murphy and others, circa 1949; 1 print of Robert Murphy, circa 1949; 1 plaque in honor of Robert Murphy, 1944; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Tracy Voorhees and others, Dec. 19, 1949; 1 print of Alben Barkley, Lucius Clay, Robert Murphy, January 19, 1949; 1 print of Alben Barkley, Lucius Clay; 1 print of Lucius Clay, Robert Murphy and others. (Envelope LL)
  - 5 unidentified prints, circa 1949; 3 prints of Robert Murphy, Mrs. Murphy and others, Belgium, circa 1949; 9 prints of Robert Murphy and others, 1949; 4 scenes, probably Belgium. (Envelope MM)
  - 6 prints of Robert Murphy and others; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Dean Acheson, John F. Dulles and others, May 23, 1949., undated (Envelope NN)
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy, Lucius Clay and others, circa 1949; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Dean Acheson, John F. Dulles and others, May, 1949; 3 prints of Robert Murphy. (Envelope mOO)
  - 3 miscellaneous prints; 6 prints of Catherine Murphy; 1 print of Mildred Murphy; 1 print of James Webb, Robert Silvercruys, April 20, 1950; 1 print of John Sherman Cooper, Dean Acheson, may, 1950; 10 reproductions of drawings of Ghent, Belgium, 1950; 1 print of George Marshall and King Leopold of Belgium, circa 1950; 2 prints of Robert Murphy, circa 1950; 5 prints of Robert Murphy and others, Belgian Congo, 1950; 1 print of Catherine Murphy; 1 print of Mildred Murphy; 1 print of Rosemary Murphy, circa 1950; 4 prints of Robert Murphy and others. (Envelope PP)
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy and Perle Mesta, 1950; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Francis Cardinal Spellman and others, 1950; 2 prints of Robert Murphy and Mrs. Murphy, Perle Mesta and others; 1 unidentified print., undated (Envelope mQQ)
  - 9 prints of Robert Murphy, Mrs. Murphy, Margaret Truman, and others, circa 1950; 4 prints of Margaret Truman, Ambassador and Mrs. Murphy and others; 1 print of Margaret Truman, Robert Murphy and others; 1 print of Margaret Truman and others; 1 print of Margaret Truman, Robert Murphy and others; 1 print of Ambassador and Mrs. Murphy, Margaret Truman, Perle Mesta and others. (Envelope RR)
  - 2 prints of Armed Forces Staff Coolege, 1952; 1 miscellaneous print, 1952; 1 print of Jerauld Wright and others; 1 print of Robert Murphy and Katsuo Okazaki; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others, Brussels, 1952; 1 print of Joseph Sullivan; 12 prints of Ambassador and Mrs. Murphy, Mildred and others, circa 1952; 1 print of Mrs. Murphy and Mildred, 1952; 5 prints of Robert Murphy and others, Japan, circa 1952; 1 print of Tracy Voorhees; 1 print of Robert Murphy; 1 print of Robert Murphy, 1952; 1 unidentified print; 1 print of Ambassador and Mrs. Murphy, Mildred and others, Japan, 1953. (Envelope SS)
  - 1 print of the President's Committee of Notre Dame, 1953, undated (Envelope mTT)
  - 2 prints of Robert Murphy and Rosemary, 1953; 3 prints of Dean Acheson, Robert Murphy and Rosemary, 1953; 2 prints of Robert Murphy and John Foster Dulles, 1953; 11 prints of Robert Murphy., undated (Envelope UU)
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy, Mark Clark and others, 1953; 6 prints of Robert Murphy, 1953; 2 prints of Robert Murphy and others at the Leaders' Conference on Inter-American Affairs of the General Federation of Women's Clubs, October 14, 1953; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Mme. Pandit, Ralph Bunche, 1953. (Envelope VV)
  - 27 prints of Robert Murphy, Mrs. Murphy, Mildred and others, Japan, 1953; 3 prints of Robert Murphy and others at the Massachusetts Committee of Catholics, Protestants and Jews, 1954; 2 prints of Robert Murphy and Tito (Josip Broz), September 17, 1954. (Envelope WW)
  - 2 prints of Robert Murphy and Paul G. Hoffman, 1954; 8 prints of Robert Murphy; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others, 1955 (Envelope XX)
  - 10 postcards of Beirut, Lebanon; 2 postcard folders of Beirut; 1 print of John Foster Dulles, circa 1956; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others, circa 1957. (Envelope YY)
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy, James Doolittle and others, 1958; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others, 1958; 3 prints of Robert Murphy, 1958; 5 prints of Robert Murphy, 1958; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Dwight Eisenhower, Nobusuke Kishi and others; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Dwight Eisenhower, Nobusuke Kishi and others; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Dwight Eisenhower, Nobusuke Kishi and others, circa 1956; 1 print of Mrs. Robert Murphy, 1958. (Envelope ZZ)
  - 36 prints of Robert Murphy, circa 1956 (Envelope AAA)
  - 14 prints of photo for Time Cover., August 25, 1958 (Envelope BBB)
  - 1 print of Richard Nixon and Raymond J. de Jaegher, 1958; 5 prints of Robert Murphy and others, Jerusalem,, 1958; 13 prints of Robert Murphy and others, Addis Ababa, 1958. (Envelope CCC)
  - 25 prints of Frances Bolton (?); 28 prints of Robert Murphy and Frances Bolton (?), undated (Envelope DDD)
  - 2 prints of Robert Murphy, Christian Herter and others, 1959; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Dwight Eisenhower and others; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Dwight Eisenhower and A. Mateos (President of Mexico) and others, 1959; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Christian Herter, Sekou Toure (President of Guinea); 1 print of Robert Murphy and Nikita Khrushchev; 4 prints of Robert Murphy and others, 1 print of Robert Murphy and Ellis O. Briggs; 4 prints of Robert Murphy, Ogden R. Reid and others, 4 prints of Robert Murphy and Ludwig Erhard; 2 prints of Robert Murphy and other, 1959; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Marguerite Higgins and others, 1959. (Envelope EEE)
  - 1 print of Reza, Shah of Iran and others, 1958; 1 print of Kwame Nkrumah of Ghana and others, 1958; 1 print of Haile Selassie and others, 1956;1 print of Prince Faisal of Iraq, 1953; 1 print of Theodore Hesburgh, Pope John XXIII, and Frank Stanton, 1959; 1 print of Robert Murphy; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others at the International Labor Organization meeting, 1959; 8 prints of Robert Murphy and others when Murphy received an honorary degree from Harvard, 1959. (Envelope FFF)
  - 18 prints of Robert Murphy on his appointment as Under Secretary of State., August 14, 1959 (Envelope GGG)
  - 1 print of Christian Herter and others., 1959 (Envelope mHHH)
  - 9 prints of Robert Murphy, circa 1960; 2 miscellaneous prints, circa 1960; 6 prints of Robert Murphy and others, 1960; 4 unidentified prints; 2 prints or Robert Murphy; 1 print of Dwight Eisenhower; 1 print of Barbara Eisenhower. (Envelope III)
  - 3 prints of Robert Murphy and others at National Council of Christians and Jews, 1961; 3 prints of Marie Straus, 1962; 1 print of Robert Murphy, 1962; 4 prints of Robert Murphy and others at The Citade, 1963; 1 print of Mrs. Murphy and others, 1963; 1 print of Robert Murphy and Mrs. Murphy, 1963; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others, 1963; 1 print of Robert Murphy addressing the National Association of manufacturers, 1964; 3 prints of Robert Murphy and others, Berlin Wall, 1964 (Envelope JJJ)
  - 4 prints of Robert Murphy and others; 5 unidentified prints; 1 print of Robert Murphy; 1 print of Dorothy Emmerson and Haru Reischauer, 1965; 2 prints of Eisaku Sato, Robert Murphy and others, January 14, 1965; 4 prints of Robert Murphy and others, circa 1965; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Kenneth Kaunda and others, 1965; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others, 1965; 1 print of Robert Murphy and others at the National Council of Christians and Jews meeting, 1966. (Envelope KKK)
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy, 1966; 11 prints of Robert Murphy and others; 17 unidentified prints; 3 prints of New York City; 1 print of Robert Murphy, Dwight Eisenhower and others, 1966; 2 prints of Robert Murphy and others, 1966; 4 prints of John K. Emmerson, Dorothy Emmerson and others, 1966. (Envelope LLL)
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy, William Knox, Felix Houphouet-Boigny, and James Farley, 1967; 1 print of the American Research Hospital in Poland, 1966; 2 prints of Robert Murphy, 1966; 1 print of Robert Murphy, James Farley and others, 1967; 2 prints of Robert Murphy and others; 7 prints of Robert Murphy and others, 1967; 2 prints of Robert Murphy; 3 prints of Robert Murphy and others at an American-German Industrial Meeting, 1974; 2 prints of Robert Murphy and Alfred de Zavas, 1975; 1 print of Alfred de Zavas. (Envelope MMM)
  - 2 prints of Robert Murphy and others at a Developing Nations Advisory Committee meeting., October, 1970 (Envelope mNNN)
  - 1 print of Henri Bertrand, 1975; miscellaneous prints, 1973; 2 prints of Robert Murphy and others, Lyndon Baines Johnson Room, U.S. Capitol, 1973; 8 negatives, circa 1945; 1 negative, 1946; 3 prints of Murphy and others, 1970;3 prints of Robert Murphy and others at presentation of honorary degree to Murphy, Marquette University, 1968; 1 miscellaneous print, 1968; 2 miscellaneous prints, 1969; 2 prints of Robert Murphy and others, circa 1967; 1 print of Nelson Rockefeller, Jackie Robinson, Sterling Brown, 1967. (Envelope OOO)
  - 1 album of prints of Robert Murphy's visit to Florennes, Belgium., 1951 (Box 144)
- Incremental Materials, 1898-2000
- Biographical File II, 1898-2000
  General note
  See also Oversize File
  Address and appointment books, articles, awards, clippings and printed matter, currency, curriculum vitae, obituary, and scrapbooks, relating to Robert Murphy's personal life and years of service, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Address books, undated (Box-folder 147: 1)
  - Appointment books
    - Undated (Box-folder 147: 2)
    - 1940-1942 (Box-folder 147: 3)
    - 1944-1947 (Box-folder 147: 4)
    - 1948-1949 (Box-folder 147: 5)
    - 1960-1963 (Box-folder 147: 6)
    - 1964-1967 (Box-folder 147: 7)
  - Articles
    - "Le Secret de Darlan," Pierre Ordioni, undated (Box-folder 147: 8)
    - "Robert Murphy: Codebreakers' Delight," David Kahn, The Nation, 1976 March 20 (Box-folder 147: 9)
    - "How Dulles Worked the Coup d'Etat," Stephen Schlesinger, The Nation, 1978 October 28 (Box-folder 147: 10)
  - Awards, certificates, citations, and honorary degrees.
    - Undated
      - Certificate, International Executive Service Corps (IESC), Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 147: 11)
      - Citation, Milwaukee High School, Wisconsin (Box-folder 148: 1)
    - 1953 November 20, Certificate, Office of the Attorney General, Texas (Box-folder 148: 2)
    - 1954 November 29, Honorary Doctor of Laws, Fordham University and University of Long Island, New York (Box-folder 148: 3)
    - 1955 June 6, Honorary Doctor of Laws, Georgetown University, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 148: 4)
      See also box 153
    - 1958 June 4, Doctor of Laws, George Washington University, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 148: 5)
    - 1959
      - January, certificate and pin, Department of State, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 148: 6)
      - May 13, Bellarmine Medal, Louisville, Kentucky. (Box-folder 148: 7)
        See also boxes 153 and 176
        Printed announcements, The Record, Louisville, Kentucky, 1959 February 20 and May 22.
      - June 1, Award of Laetare Medal, University of Notre Dame, Indiana. (Box-folder 148: 8)
        Printed copy, Congressional Record, 1959 June. Includes related material
      - June 7, honorary doctor of laws, Saint Joseph's College, Philadelphia. (Box-folder 148: 9)
        See also boxes 153 and 182
        Printed program.
      - June 11, doctor of laws, Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts. (Box-folder 148: 10)
        Printed program and related material
    - 1960 June 8, honorary doctor of laws, New York University (Box-folder 148: 11)
    - 1965 October 27, Citation, Roosevelt Medal, Theodore Roosevelt Association, New York (Box-folder 149: 1)
    - 1966 June, honorary doctor of laws, Rockhurst College, Kansas City, Missouri (Box-folder 149: 2)
    - 1974 February 25, Certificate of Appreciation, Founder and Honorary Citizen, Boystown, Korea. Includes a letter from Korean Relief, Inc. (Box-folder 149: 3)
      Includes a letter from Korean Relief, Inc., 1974 March
    - 1977 May 18, William J. Donovan Award, Veterans of the Office of Strategic Services (OSS). Printed program (Box-folder 149: 4)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1953-2000
    Photographs found among clippings were moved to the Photographs series
    - 1953 (Box-folder 149: 5)
    - 1954
      - January-September 17 (Box-folder 149: 6)
      - September 18 - December 9 (Box-folder 149: 7)
    - 1955
      - Month unknown (Box-folder 149: 8)
      - March-October (Box-folder 149: 9)
    - 1956 June-November (Box-folder 149: 10)
    - 1957
      - Month unknown (Box-folder 149: 11)
      - March-December (Box-folder 149: 12)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 149: 13-18)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 150: 1-6)
    - 1959
      - January-April (Box-folder 150: 7-9)
      - June-December (Box-folder 150: 10)
    - 1964-1968 (Box-folder 150: 11)
    - 2000 (Box-folder 150: 12)
  - Currency, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 150: 13)
  - Curriculum vitae, undated (Box-folder 150: 14)
  - Obituary, 1978 (Box-folder 150: 15)
    Includes eulogy, letter and telegram of condolence, 1978 June, and a note regarding acceptance of contribution in Robert Murphy's name, 1978 August 15
  - Scrapbooks
    - 1898-1940 (Box-folder 151: 1-10)
      Brochures, circulars, clippings, correspondence, notes, photographs, press release, printed matter, programs, reports, speeches, and miscellany, titled "The Morgue," relating to early years of Robert Murphy's service
    - 1950-1951 (Box-folder 152: 1-5)
      Clippings, photographs, and postcards relating to Eleanor Roosevelt's visit to Belgium, Robert Murphy's years of service as ambassador to Belgium, his visits to the American Women's Club and to the Belgian Congo
  - Miscellany, 1954 (Box-folder 152: 6)
- Speeches and Writings II, 1947-1977
  Articles, books, interviews, lectures, notes, reviews of Robert Murphy's books, texts of speeches, and related correspondence, arranged chronologically
  - General
    - General (Box-folder 153: 1-4)
    - Notes (Box-folder 153: 5)
  - "Japanese-American Trends,", undated (Box-folder 153: 6)
    Typescript
  - Proposed remarks, luncheon in honor of Lebanese Premier Karame, undated (Box-folder 153: 7)
  - Review of Milton Viorst, Hostile Allies: FDR and Charles de Gaulle, undated (Box-folder 153: 8)
  - "Why Are We in Berlin?", undated (Box-folder 153: 9)
  - Commencement address, Thomas A. Roberts High School, Berlin, Germany, 1947 July 11 (Box-folder 153: 10)
    Typescript. Includes related material
  - Speech, U.S. Information Policy in Germany, Berlin, Germany, 1947 October 4 (Box-folder 153: 11)
    Typescript notes. Includes a letter from Thomas B. Stauffer, 1947 September 30
  - Speech, American Women's Club, Berlin, Germany, 1948 January 6 (Box-folder 153: 12)
  - Commencement address, Thomas A. Roberts High School, Berlin, Germany, 1948 June 15 (Box-folder 153: 13)
    Typescript. Includes related materials
  - Remarks on the German problem, National Advertising Council meeting, White House, 1949 February 9 (Box-folder 153: 14)
  - "The United States Looks at the United Nations," address, convention of the Texas Congress of Parents and Teachers, San Antonio, Texas, 1953 November 19 (Box-folder 153: 15)
    Typescript press release
  - "Tomorrow's Diplomacy," commencement address, Georgetown University, 1955 June 6 (Box-folder 153: 16)
    See also box 148
    Printed copy.
  - "The Defense of Asia," article, Military Review, 1955 December (Box-folder 153: 17)
    Printed copy